I consider it my life's mission
أعتبرها مهمتي في الحياة
to convey the urgency of climate change through my work.
في أن أقنع من خلال لوحاتي بالإستعجالية التي يفرضها التغير المناخي
I've traveled north to the Arctic to the capture the unfolding story
سافرت إلى القطب الشمالي لإلتقاط القصة المتجلية
of polar melt,
في الذوبان القطبي،
and south to the Equator to document the subsequent rising seas.
و سافرت إلى خط الإستواء لتوثيق إرتفاع منسوب المياه الناتج عنه.
Most recently, I visited the icy coast of Greenland
مؤخرا زرت ساحل جرينلاند الجليدي
and the low-lying islands of the Maldives,
و الجزر المنخفضة لجمهورية المالديف.
connecting two seemingly disparate but equally endangered
لأصل بين منطقيتين مختلفتين ظاهريا لكن مهددتين على حد سواء
parts of our planet.
من هذا العالم.
My drawings explore moments of transition, turbulence
تكتشف رسوماتي لحظات الإنتقال و الإضطراب
and tranquility in the landscape,
و السكينة في المنظر الطبيعي.
allowing viewers to emotionally connect
ما يسمح للمشاهدين بربط اتصال عاطفي
with a place you might never have the chance to visit.
مع مكان قد لا تسمح لهم الفرصة بزيارته.
I choose to convey the beauty as opposed to the devastation.
أختار أن أقنعكم بالجمال بدل الدمار.
If you can experience the sublimity of these landscapes,
إذا استطعتم تجربة جَلاَل هذه المناظر الطبيعية
perhaps you'll be inspired to protect and preserve them.
لربما ستقتنعون بالمحافظة عليها و حمايتها.
Behavioral psychology tells us that we take action
يبين علم النفس السلوكي أننا نبادر بالمساهمة
and make decisions based on our emotions above all else.
و نتخذ قرارات مبنية على المشاعر بدل كل شيء.
And studies have shown that art impacts our emotions
و أظهرت الدراسات أن الفن يؤثر على مشاعرنا
more effectively than a scary news report.
بفعالية أكبر من تقرير تلفزيوني مرعب.
Experts predict ice-free Arctic summers
يتوقع الخبراء أن صيف القطب الشمالي سيكون خاليا من الجليد
as early as 2020.
بحلول 2020.
And sea levels are likely to rise between two and ten feet
و أن مستويات البحر سترتفع على الأرجح بمقدار قدمين إلى ثلاث
by century's end.
بحلول نهاية القرن.
I have dedicated my career to illuminating these projections
لقد كرست حياتي المهنية لتسليط الضوء على هذه التخمينات
with an accessible medium,
بواسطة وسيلة متوفرة للجميع،
one that moves us in a way that statistics may not.
قادرة على التأثير فينا بعكس الإحصاءات.
My process begins with traveling to the places
تبدأ عمليتي بالسفر إلى تلك الأماكن
at the forefront of climate change.
على خط الجبهة مع التغير المناخي.
On-site, I take thousands of photographs.
ألتقط الآلاف من الصور في الموقع .
Back in the studio,
و في الورشة،
I work from both my memory of the experience and the photographs
أعمل استنادا إلى ذاكرتي عن التجربة و الصور
to create very large-scale compositions,
لخلق لوحات كبيرة الحجم،
sometimes over 10 feet wide.
بعضها يفوق عرضه العشرة أقدام.
I draw with soft pastel, which is dry like charcoal, but colors.
و أرسم بأقلام الباستيل الشبيهة بالفحم لكنها ملونة
I consider my work drawings but others call them painting.
أعتبر أعمالي بمثابة رسومات بينما يعتبرها الآخرون لوحات
I cringe, though, when I'm referred to as a "finger painter."
و أستاء عندما يدعونني بـ"الرسامة بالإصبع."
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
But I don't use any tools
لكنني لا أستعمل أيَّ أدوات.
and I have always used my fingers and palms
و لطالما استعملت أصابعي و كفي
to manipulate the pigment on the paper.
للتلاعب بالصِباغ على الورق.
Drawing is a form of meditation for me.
أعتبر الرسم بمثابة نوع من التأمل.
It quiets my mind.
فهو يبعث على السكينة.
I don't perceive what I'm drawing
أنا لا أعتبر ما أرسم
as ice or water.
ماءً أو جليداً.
Instead, the image is stripped down
بدل ذلك تُجرد الصورة
to its most basic form of color and shape.
إلى شكلها الرئيسي من لون و شكل.
Once the piece is complete,
حالما تكتمل اللوحة،
I can finally experience the composition as a whole,
أستطيع إختبارها بكليتها
as an iceberg floating through glassy water,
كجبل جليدي يطفو فوق المياه الزجاجية،
or a wave cresting with foam.
أو أمواج مزبدة بالرغوة.
On average, a piece this size takes me about,
في المتوسط يتطلب مني رسم لوحة بهذا الحجم
as you can see, 10 seconds.
كما ترون 10 ثواني.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
(Applause)
(تصفيق)
Really, more like 200 hours, 250 hours for something that size.
بل 200 إلى 250 ساعة تقريبا للوحة بهذا الحجم
But I've been drawing ever since I could hold a crayon, really.
لكنني كنت أرسم منذ أن كنت قادرة على حمل القلم.
My mom was an artist, and growing up,
كانت أمي فنانة، و خلال فترة نموي،
we always had art supplies all over the house.
كانت مستلزمات الرسم في كل أرجاء المنزل.
My mother's love of photography
حب أمي للتصوير
propelled her to the most remote regions of the earth,
أخدها إلى أكثر الأماكن النائية على الأرض،
and my family and I were fortunate enough
و كنت أنا و عائلتي محظوظين
to join and support her on these adventures.
للإنضمام إليها و دعمها في تلك المغامرات.
We rode camels in Northern Africa
ركبنا الجمال في شمال إفريقيا
and mushed on dog sleds near the North Pole.
و سُقنا زلاجات الكلاب قرب القطب الجنوبي.
In August of 2012, I led my first expedition,
في أغسطس /آب من عام 2012 قدت بعتثي الأولى،
taking a group of artists and scholars up the northwest coast of Greenland.
أخدت معي فنانين و علماء إلى شمال غرب ساحل جرينلاند.
My mother was originally supposed to lead this trip.
كان من المفترض أن تقود أمي هذه الرحلة.
She and I were in the early stages of planning,
كنت و إياها في المراحل الأولى من التخطيط.
as we had intended to go together,
و نوينا الذهاب معا.
when she fell victim to a brain tumor.
عندما أصيبت بورم في الدماغ
The cancer quickly took over her body and mind,
سرعان ما سيطر على عقلها و جسدها
and she passed away six months later.
و وافتها المنية بعد ستة أشهر.
During the months of her illness, though,
لكن خلال أشهر مرضها،
her dedication to the expedition never wavered, and I made a promise
لم يتزحزح تفانيها للبعثة أبدا، و قطعت وعدا
to carry out her final journey.
بأن أكمل الرحلة من بعدها.
My mother's passion for the Arctic
تردد صدى شغف أمي بالقطب الجنوبي عبر تجربتي في جرينلاند.
and I felt the power
و أحسست بقوةِ
and the fragility of the landscape.
و ضعفِ الطبيعة.
The sheer size of the icebergs
الحجم الهائل للجبال الجليدية
is humbling.
يبعث على التواضع.
The ice fields are alive with movement and sound
الحقول الجليدية عامرة بالحركة و الصوت
in a way that I never expected.
بطرق لم أتوقعها أبدا.
I expanded the scale of my compositions
كبَّرتُ من حجم لوحاتي
to give you that same sense of awe that I experienced.
لإعطائكم نفس إحساس الدهشة الذي عِشته
Yet, while the grandeur of the ice is evident,
لكن رغم أن بَهَاء الثلج جَلِيّ
so, too, is its vulnerability.
إلا أن ضعفه كذلك أيضا.
From our boat,
من قاربنا
I could see the ice sweating under the unseasonably warm sun.
استطعت رؤية الجليد يتعرق تحت وطأة حرارة الشمس غير الموسمية
We had a chance to visit many of the Inuit communities in Greenland
حظينا بفرصة زيارة العديد من مجتمعات الإسكيمو في جرينلاند
that now face huge challenges.
الذين يواجهون تحديا كبيرا.
The locals spoke to me of vast areas of sea ice
أخبرني السكان المحليون عن مناطق بحرية متجمدة واسعة
that are no longer freezing over as they once did.
لم تعد تتجمد كما في السابق.
And without ice, their hunting and harvesting grounds
و من دون جليد ستؤول مناطق الزراعة و الصيد
are severely diminished,
إلى الزوال
threatening their way of life and survival.
و تهدد طرق عيشهم و بقائهم.
The melting glaciers in Greenland
إن الكتل الجليدية الذائبة في جرينلاند
are one of the largest contributing factors to rising sea levels,
من أكبر العوامل المساهمة في إرتفاع منسوب المياه
which have already begun to drown
و الذي بدأ بالفعل بإغراق
some of our world's lowest-lying islands.
بعض أخفض الجزر على الأرض.
One year after my trip to Greenland, I visited the Maldives,
بعد زيارتي لجرينلاند بسنة، زرت جزر المالديف
the lowest and flattest country in the entire world.
البلد الأكثر انخفاضا و تسطحا في العالم.
While I was there, I collected images and inspiration
و أنا هناك أخدت صورا و إلهاما
for a new body of work:
لمجموعة أعمالي الجديدة:
drawings of waves lapping on the coast of a nation
رسومات لأمواج تلعق ساحل أمة
that could be entirely underwater within this century.
على شفير أن تكون تحت الماء بالكامل خلال هذا القرن
Devastating events happen every day
تحدث الوقائع المدمرة كل يوم
on scales both global and personal.
على الصعيدين العالمي و الشخصي.
When I was in Greenland,
عندما كنت في جرينلاند
I scattered my mother's ashes amidst the melting ice.
نثرت رماد أمي في ثنايا الجليد الذائب.
Now she remains a part of the landscape she loved so much,
الآن ستبقى جزءا من الطبيعة التي أحبت كثيرا
even as it, too, passes and takes on new form.
حتى و إن كانت ستتحول لتتخذ شكلا جديدا
Among the many gifts my mother gave me
كان من ضمن العديد من الهدايا التي أهدتني أمي
was the ability to focus on the positive,
القدرة على التركيز على الإيجابي،
rather than the negative.
بدل السلبي.
My drawings celebrate the beauty of what we all stand to lose.
تحتفي لوحاتي بالجمال الذي سنخسره جميعا.
I hope they can serve as records of sublime landscapes in flux,
آمل أن تكون لوحاتي بمثابة سجلات للمناظر الطبيعية الخلابة و المتغيرة باستمرار.
documenting the transition and inspiring our global community
مُوثقة للتغير المناخي و مُلهمة للمجتمع العالمي
to take action for the future.
للمبادرة بما سيصلح لمستقبلنا.
Thank you.
شكرا لكم.
(Applause)
(تصفيق)